<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- Copyright 2025-2026 The MathWorks, Inc. -->
<rsccat version="1.0" locale="en_US" product="matlab-mcp-core-server">
    <message>
        <entry key="HelpDescription">Show this help text</entry>
        <entry key="VersionDescription">Display the version of this MCP server.</entry>
        <entry key="SetupMATLABDescription">Set up a MATLAB installation for use with the MATLAB MCP Core Server.</entry>
        <entry key="DisableTelemetryDescription">This MCP server can collect fully anonymized information about your usage of the server and send it to MathWorks. This data collection helps MathWorks improve products and is on by default. To opt out of data collection, set the argument --disable-telemetry to true.</entry>
        <entry key="UseSingleMATLABSessionDescription">By default, this MCP server starts a single MATLAB session, and stops the session when the server shuts down. To allow the server to manage multiple MATLAB sessions, set this argument to false. </entry>
        <entry key="BaseDirDescription">The folder where this MCP server stores log files. If not specified, the server uses the default temp folder of your operating system.</entry>
        <entry key="LogLevelDescription">The log levels of this MCP server. Valid values, in order of decreasing verbosity, are 'debug', 'info', 'warn', and 'error'.</entry>
        <entry key="PreferredLocalMATLABRootDescription">Full path specifying which MATLAB to start. Do not include /bin in the path. By default, the server tries to find the first MATLAB on the system PATH.</entry>
        <entry key="PreferredMATLABStartingDirectoryDescription">Specify the folder where MATLAB starts. If you do not provide the argument, MATLAB starts in these locations: Linux: /home/username, Windows: C:\Users\username\Documents, Mac: /Users/username/Documents.</entry>
        <entry key="InternalUseDescription">INTERNAL USE ONLY</entry>
        <entry key="InitializeMATLABOnStartupDescription">To initialize MATLAB as soon as you start the server, set this argument to true. By default, MATLAB only starts when the first tool is called. </entry>
        <entry key="DisplayModeDescription">Specify whether to show the MATLAB desktop. Use 'desktop' mode (default) to show the MATLAB desktop or 'nodesktop' mode to use MATLAB only from your AI application, without the MATLAB desktop. </entry>
        <entry key="MATLABSessionModeDescription">Specify how MATLAB sessions are managed. Use 'new' (default) to launch new MATLAB sessions from a local installation, or 'existing' to connect to an already running MATLAB instance.</entry>
        <entry key="ExtensionFileDescription">Use custom MCP tools by providing the path to a JSON extension file that defines the tools. Each tool maps to a MATLAB function. You can use the argument multiple times to specify multiple extension files. If you do not specify an extension file, the MCP server does not load any custom tools.</entry>
        <entry key="SuccessfullySetupMATLAB">Successfully setup MATLAB.</entry>
    </message>
</rsccat>
